{
  "theme": [
    {
      "Questions": [
        {
          "Question": "Which cartoon features four turtles named after Renaissance artists?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Scooby-Doo",
            "Powerpuff Girls",
            "Dexter's Laboratory"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles, created in 1984, was a massive hit, leading to comics, TV shows, and movies."
        },
        {
          "Question": "What is the name of the adventurous dog and his human companion in a 90s animated series?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Courage the Cowardly Dog",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "SpongeBob SquarePants",
            "The Powerpuff Girls",
            "Dexter's Laboratory"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Courage, a timid purple dog with supernatural enemies, and his owners live in the middle of Nowhere, where bizarre things happen."
        },
        {
          "Question": "In 'Hey Arnold!', what is the name of the boarding house Arnold lives in with his grandparents?",
          "TrueAnswer": "P.S. 118",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Hillwood",
            "Sunnyside",
            "Holly Wood"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Arnold lives in a fictional community called Hillwood and attends the fictional P.S. 118; the show reflects urban life."
        },
        {
          "Question": "What is the name of the anthropomorphic sponge living in a pineapple under the sea?",
          "TrueAnswer": "SpongeBob SquarePants",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Tom and Jerry",
            "The Rugrats",
            "The Flintstones"
          ],
          "Explanation": "SpongeBob SquarePants first aired in 1999 and spawned successful movies, merchandise, and a Broadway musical."
        },
        {
          "Question": "What is the name of the smartest member of the 'The Powerpuff Girls' trio?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Blossom",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Buttercup",
            "Bubbles",
            "Mojo Jojo"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Blossom, a natural leader, represented intelligence among the three kindergarten-aged superhero girls created by Professor Utonium."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which cartoon follows a group of babies as they explore the world from their viewpoint?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Rugrats",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "The Flintstones",
            "Tom and Jerry",
            "Scooby-Doo"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Rugrats, created by Arlene Klasky, Gábor Csupó, and Paul Germain, was critically acclaimed and popular among audiences."
        },
        {
          "Question": "What are the names of the two siblings becoming superheroes following an accident involving chemical X?",
          "TrueAnswer": "The Powerpuff Girls",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Dexter's Laboratory",
            "SpongeBob SquarePants",
            "Courage the Cowardly Dog"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Blossom, Bubbles, and Buttercup are kindergarten-aged superheroes, created in 1998, who save Townsville from villains."
        },
        {
          "Question": "In 'Dexter's Laboratory', what is the name of Dexter's sister who frequently ruins his experiments?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Dee Dee",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Maddie",
            "Lily",
            "Cindy"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Dee Dee's distracting presence serves as a recurring source of irritation for the boy genius, Dexter."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Who leads a team of crime-fighting dogs and is the alter ego of a mild-mannered janitor?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Underdog",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Scooby-Doo",
            "Astro",
            "Clifford the Big Red Dog"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Underdog, voiced by Wally Cox, was a humble shoe shiner named Shoeshine Boy who transformed into the superhero 'Underdog'."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which cartoon character is known for his famous catchphrase 'What's up, doc?'",
          "TrueAnswer": "Bugs Bunny",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Mickey Mouse",
            "Popeye",
            "Daffy Duck"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Bugs Bunny, created in 1940, became an iconic symbol and the mascot for Warner Bros. and is known for his wit and charm."
        },
        {
          "Question": "In 'Scooby-Doo', who is the owner of the Mystery Machine van?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Norville 'Shaggy' Rogers",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Fred Jones",
            "Velma Dinkley",
            "Daphne Blake"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Shaggy, along with his great dane, Scooby-Doo, are known for their unusual appetites and cowardice in the face of danger."
        },
        {
          "Question": "What is the name of the talking cat who is the protector of her owner, Sabrina?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Salem",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Garfield",
            "Tom",
            "Felix the Cat"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Salem Saberhagen is a 500-year-old witch who was sentenced to spend 100 years as a cat for attempting world domination."
        },
        {
          "Question": "What is the name of the villain in 'The Smurfs' who is known for wearing black clothing?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Gargamel",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Azrael",
            "Brainy Smurf",
            "Papa Smurf"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Gargamel, an evil wizard, aim to use the Smurfs to create a potion that would grant him ultimate power and immortality."
        },
        {
          "Question": "What is the name of the king who rules over Thundera in 'ThunderCats'?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Lion-O",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Grune",
            "Panthro",
            "Mumm-Ra"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Lion-O is the leader of the ThunderCats and is depicted wielding the Sword of Omens, which gives him sight beyond sight."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which cartoon features a clumsy teenager with the ability to transform into a superhero by shouting 'Shazam!'?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Shazam!/Isis Hour",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Captain Planet",
            "The Powerpuff Girls",
            "The Smurfs"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The show 'Shazam!' follows Billy Batson, and when he says the magic word 'Shazam!', he transforms into the superhero Captain Marvel."
        },
        {
          "Question": "In 'He-Man and the Masters of the Universe', what is the name of He-Man's arch-nemesis?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Skeletor",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Beast Man",
            "Man-At-Arms",
            "King Hiss"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Skeletor's goal is to conquer Castle Grayskull and gain the secrets and powers it contains, often fighting He-Man."
        },
        {
          "Question": "In 'Voltron: Defender of the Universe', what are the names of the five robotic lions that form Voltron?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Black, Red, Green, Blue, Yellow",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Lance, Pidge, Keith, Hunk, Allura",
            "Megatron, Optimus, Bumblebee, Starscream, Soundwave",
            "Mighty, Tiny, Major, Leader, Smart"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The series follows a team of astronauts who pilot a giant super robot known as 'Voltron' to protect the universe."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Who is the main villain in the 'Transformers' series?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Megatron",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Optimus Prime",
            "Starscream",
            "Bumblebee"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Megatron, leader of the Decepticons, is a powerful and ruthless adversary of the Autobots in the Transformers series."
        },
        {
          "Question": "In 'G.I. Joe: A Real American Hero', what is the name of the elite special mission force's mortal enemy?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Cobra",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Serpentor",
            "Destro",
            "Zartan"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Cobra, led by Cobra Commander, wages a continuous battle against G.I. Joe for worldwide control and domination."
        },
        {
          "Question": "What is the name of the team of teenage mutants trained to be ninjas by Master Splinter?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Teen Titans",
            "X-Men",
            "Power Rangers"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The Turtles' original comic book series, created by Kevin Eastman and Peter Laird, was published in 1984."
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}